<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>THETA 360 Developers Unofficial Blog</title>
    <description>RICOH THETA developer community blog. Tips on using the RICOH THETA S  360 degree camera. The API is based on Open Spherical Camera (OSC) specification 
</description>
    <link>http://theta360developers.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://theta360developers.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 11:37:54 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 11:37:54 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>RICOH THETA Developer Community Services</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The RICOH THETA S is an extremely exciting product. We’re at the beginning
of a larger movement for the general public to use 360 images and 360 videos.
Every week, I learn new things about what major companies are doing
with 360 images and videos. Facebook, YouTube, Google, The New York Times, are
just a few of many organizations that are now supporting 360 media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My colleague, Jesse Casman, and I are helping RICOH with technical
marketing activities in the US. Although, we are outside consultants,
we feel like we’re part of a much larger community that includes RICOH,
independent developers, enthusiasts, companies, and frankly, anyone
that thinks that 360 pictures and videos are cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we are technical marketers, we’re super enthusiastic about
developers and are trying to figure out if there’s anything we can do
with limited resources. Feedback from developers is important. The services
are for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is our plan to provide basic help to you with our limited resources and
limited technical knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forumhttpsdeveloperstheta360comenforums&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.theta360.com/en/forums/&quot;&gt;Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesse and I will go into the forum and answer questions when  we can. For the
questions that we can’t answer, we’ll rely on the community. If the question
relates to a broad group of people, we will try and replicate the problem
and then report back to RICOH engineers. An example of a problem we’ll
escalate is a problem with an application due to changes in Adobe Air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain requests for information that RICOH can’t provide. For example,
RICOH can’t release lens parameter information or stitching library algorithms.
For these questions, we will respond that RICOH can’t provide the information
and organize the requests so that RICOH managers have an understand of
what the community is requesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;github-repository-managementhttpsgithubcomtheta360developers&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/theta360developers&quot;&gt;GitHub Repository Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will organize code examples from the community. The examples cover both
the control of the camera as well as basic functionality such as viewing a
equirectangular image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, we will either test the code ourselves or get help from the community
in testing the code. If the listing becomes too large, we will organize the
repositories into sub-directories and categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bloghttptheta360developersgithubioblog&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theta360developers.github.io/blog/&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of great content out there about using the RICOH THETA S.
Some of it is in Japanese and a lot of it is in English.
The developer community in Japan is very active. Jesse can
read Japanese quickly and
I can struggle through it. We’ll combine content from Japan with
English content and provide articles in English about viewing and
streaming content, controlling the camera with the API and using
THETA products and media with other tools or services from companies
like Google, Facebook, Oculus, and Unity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;community-guidehttptheta360developersgithubiocommunity-documentcommunityhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theta360developers.github.io/community-document/community.html&quot;&gt;Community Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re building a community guide based on questions and responses about the
most common topics. Hopefully, we’ll be able to pull popular topics from the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://theta360developers.github.io/blog/community/2015/12/17/theta-s-community-assistance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theta360developers.github.io/blog/community/2015/12/17/theta-s-community-assistance.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>community</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
